examine.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy Policy | Examine.com

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Examine.com Inc. (“Examine.com” or “Examine”) collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "User") of the http://examine.com website ("Site"). This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by Examine.com.

## Personal identification information

We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our site, register on the site, place an order, fill out a form, respond to a survey, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address. Users may, however, visit our Site anonymously. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities.

## Non-personal identification information

We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

## Web browser cookies

Our Site may use "cookies" to enhance User experience. User's web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. Users may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly.

## How we use collected information 

Examine.com may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes:

1

##### To run and operate our Site

We may need your information display content on the Site correctly.

2

##### To improve customer service

Information you provide helps us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.

3

##### To personalize user experience

We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site.

4

##### To improve our Site

We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services.

5

##### To process payments

We may use the information Users provide about themselves when placing an order only to provide service to that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service.

6

##### To run a promotion, contest, survey or other Site feature

To send Users information they agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to them.

7

##### To manage product reviews and ratings

We may use third party service providers to help us manage product reviews and ratings left by Users.

8

##### To send periodic emails

We may use the email address to send User information and updates pertaining to their order. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests.

## How we protect your information

Your personal information will be kept confidential. It is stored and processed on servers located in Canada and the United States of America maintained by our third-party service providers. Your personal information will be subject to the laws of those jurisdictions, including laws that allow for law enforcement access. These laws may be different from the laws of the jurisdiction in which you reside. We use administrative, procedural and technical safeguards to protect your information against loss or theft as well as against unauthorized access or disclosure in order to protect your privacy.

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site. While we use reasonable efforts to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit using the Internet, third party digital networks, websites, mobile devices, the Site, or any social media platform.

We cannot be responsible for Internet fraud or theft. Please keep this in mind when providing information through the Site.

## Sharing your personal information

We do not sell, trade, or rent Users personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above. We may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission.

**WARNING:** Do not share/send personal information (and particularly financial/credit card information) in response to any unsolicited e-mail or phone call that appears to come from Examine.com. We will not contact you and ask for such information; such information is only submitted when completing an order.

## Electronic newsletters

If User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email or User may contact us via our Site. We may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission.

## Third party websites

Users may find advertising or other content on our Site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licencors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website's own terms and policies.

Examine.com is not responsible for any damages arising from and expressly disclaims any liability associated with how third parties collect, store, use or disclose your personal information. If you choose to visit one of these websites, you should review the privacy policies that govern those particular websites.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

Examine.com has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will post a notification on the main page of our Site. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

## Your acceptance of these terms

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us.

This document was last updated on Jan 1, 2018.
